(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-13T23:01:09.655092",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
跳ねた 跳ねた 僕は跳ねた
I bound, I bound, I bound,
小学生みたいに
like an elementary school kid,
雨上がりの夜に跳ねた
I bound into the night after the rain,
水切りみたいに
like a skipping stone.
（見ていたふりして）
(Pretending to watch...)
明日を素通り
Passing right by tomorrow,
（夜に逃げただけ）
(Just escaping into the night...)
朝を素通り
Passing right by the morning.
跳ねた 跳ねた 君も跳ねた
You bound, you bound, you bound too,
女学生みたいに
like a schoolgirl,
水たまりの上で跳ねた
bounding over puddles,
アメンボみたいに
like a water strider.
（忘れたふりして）
(Pretending to forget...)
それはつまり
Which simply means,
（夜に逃げただけ）
(just escaping into the night.)
どこへ行こう
Where shall we go?
ここに居ようとしてる？
Are you trying to stay here?
逃げるよ
We'll run away,
we'll run away,
あと少しだけ
for just a little longer.
消えた 消えた 君が消えた
You vanished, vanished, vanished,
蜃気楼みたいに
like a mirage.
音も消えた
Sound faded away
さよなら言うように
As if saying goodbye
キコエタフリシテ
Pretending I heard
君の言う通り
Just as you said
ヨルニニゲタダケ
I just escaped into the night
どこへ行こう
Where shall we go?
ここに居ようとしてる？
Are you trying to stay here?
逃げても
Even if I run
音はもうしなくて
There's no sound anymore
雨になって何分後かに行く
Turning into rain, moving forward minutes later
今泣いて何分後かに行く
Crying now, moving forward minutes later
今泣いて何分後の自分
Crying now, who will I be minutes later?
今泣いて何分後かに行く
Crying now, moving forward minutes later
今泣いて何分後かに言ふ
Crying now, speaking up minutes later
今泣いて何年後の自分
Crying now, who will I be years later?
行けるよ
I can go
遠くへ行こうとしてる
Trying to go far away
イメージしよう
Let's picture it
自分が思うほうへ
Towards the direction I choose
雨になって何分後かに行く
Turning into rain, moving forward minutes later
今泣いて何分後かに行く
Crying now, moving forward minutes later
今泣いて何分後の自分
Crying now, who will I be minutes later?
今泣いて何分後かに言ふ
Crying now, speaking up minutes later
今泣いて何年後の自分
Crying now, who will I be years later?
笑っていたいんだろう
You want to be smiling, right?
はい、ということで！
Alright, so!
#holoAcousticLive 始まりました！
The #holoAcousticLive has begun!
ということでね
So then,
楽しいね！
This is so much fun!
1曲目はしっとりに始まったかと思いきや、元気に行く『夜の踊り子』で
We thought the first song started off mellow, but it turned into an energetic 'Yoru no Odoriko'...
スタートさせていただきましたー！
...to kick off the concert!
最高でした！
That was awesome!
ちょっと気持ちよく...
It felt so good...
最後に...
At the end...
もう行きそびれましたけどね
I almost missed my queue, though!
はい、失礼いたしました！ということで
Yes, sorry about that! So anyway,
えー、本日一緒に歌ってくださるメンバーがあと2人いるので、全員呼んじゃいたいと思います！
Um, we have two more members joining us to sing today, so I'd like to call everyone out!
どうぞー！
Come on out!
おいおいおいおい！
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
盛り上がりすぎじゃない？
Aren't you guys getting a bit too hyped?
カメラワークとかこだわってましたね
They really put a lot of detail into the camera work!
MVっぽい感じでね、やってくださった人がすごいこだわって
It felt like a music video; the team working on it was super meticulous.
チース！チース！
Hey! Hey!
それでは！
Alright then!
まずは、今日一緒に歌っていただく皆さん、自己紹介をお願いしたいと思いまーす！まずはAZKiから！
First, I'd like to ask everyone singing with us today to introduce themselves! Starting with AZKi!
はい！コンコンコンコン AZKi！
Hi! Kon-kon-kon-kon AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図！あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー、AZKiでーす！よろしくお願いします！
Microphone in my right hand, map in my left! Zero Guesser of your heart, I'm AZKi! Pleased to be here!
第2回に引き続き！ありがとうございます！
Continuing on from the 2nd stream! Thank you so much!
第2回も呼んでいただきありがとうございます
Thank you for inviting me for the 2nd time as well!
「第2回いつあるんですか？」ってAZKiがちょいちょい聞いてくれたから
AZKi kept asking me, "When is the 2nd stream happening?"
「もう一回やろう」っていう勇気につながったんで、感謝しております！
...which gave me the courage to do it again, so I'm truly grateful!
お願いしまーす！
Looking forward to working with you!
そして、トワさまー！
And next, Towa-sama!
はい！小悪魔VTuber... ホロライブ4期生...
Yes! Devilish VTuber... Hololive 4th Generation...
ここ大事だから！
Because this part is important!
ホロライブの... えー、常闇トワでーす！よろしくお願いいたします！
...of Hololive... um, I'm Tokoyami Towa! Pleased to meet you!
トワさまー！
Towa-sama!
嬉しい！マブと思ってますので、勝手にね
I'm so glad! I consider us besties, entirely on my own!
温度感違いますけど大丈夫ですか？
Our energy levels are completely different, but is that okay?
よろしくお願いします
Nice to meet you!
そして なんと今日のために インドネシアから日本に来てくれた こぼー！
And next, coming all the way from Indonesia to Japan just for today, it's Kobo!
ハーイ！こぼこぼ！Kobo Kanaeru at your service! Let me be your sun to shine your day!
Hi! Kobo Kobo! Kobo Kanaeru at your service! Let me be your sun to shine your day!
Ahem! Kobo Kanaeru, rain shaman this, from Hololive HoloHero! よろしくお願いします！
Ahem! Kobo Kanaeru, rain shaman, from Hololive HoloHero! Nice to meet you!
HoloHero!
イエーイ！
Yay!
テリマカシ！
Terima kasih!
サマサマ！どういたしましてって意味ね
Sama-sama! That means "you're welcome," right?
サマサマ！
Sama-sama!
来てもらえて本当に嬉しい！もう1曲目からね ご一緒させてもらいましたけど
We're so happy you could join us! We got to sing together from the very first song!
この後もよろしくお願いします！
We look forward to working with you for the rest of the show!
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
ノリノリで可愛い！でもね 始まる前「緊張する…」って言ってた
So energetic and cute! But before we started, she said, "I'm nervous..."
いやいやいや！見せてた先輩！
No no no! You were watching, Senpai!
ううん 堂々と…
No, you were so confident...
めっちゃ 自信ある！
I have super confidence!
オッケー！かっこいいHoloHero！
Okay! Cool HoloHero!
ベリーグッド！
Very good!
では続きまして 歌声が大好きな ニコタン！
Next up, someone whose singing voice I love... Niko-tan!
ニコタンが来たー！ホロライブ DEV_IS FLOW GLOW…
Niko-tan is here! From Hololive DEV_IS FLOW GLOW...
えーっと…
Um...
すごい深々とお辞儀した！
That was a super deep bow!
知らなかった人もいるかもしれないですけども、はい、ニコタン！
Some of you might not know her yet, but yes, Niko-tan!
ホロライブプロダクション所属 FLOW GLOWの 小花衣モモ… 嘘です、ニコタンだよー！
From Hololive Production FLOW GLOW, Kohana Momo... Just kidding, I'm Niko-tan!
何もなかったね
Nothing happened, right?
ここ最近ちょっと自己紹介が変わったりしてね。ちょっと緊張してますね、ニコたん。
Her self-introduction changed a bit recently, didn't it? Niko-tan, you seem a bit nervous.
もう1曲歌ったしね。歌うと脳が切り替わっちゃって…
We already sang one song. When I sing, my brain switches mode...
あ、そうなの？喋れなくなるの？
Oh, really? You can't speak properly?
あ、今歌モードになってるの？そう、今日はもう喋れませんから…
Ah, so you're in singing mode right now? Yeah, so I can't talk today...
じゃあちょっとこのまま置いておこうと思います。え、なんでですか！
Then I guess we'll just leave you be like this. Eh, why!
いや本当に呼んでくれてありがとう！こちらこそ！一緒に歌えるのがすごく嬉しくて
No really, thank you so much for inviting me! Likewise! I'm so happy we get to sing together!
次はしっとりいきますね。いきましょう！
Next, we're going with something mellow. Let's do it!
楽しみにしております！ありがとうございます！
Looking forward to it! Thank you so much!
そして、えー、ホロライブ6期生Secret Society holoXの頭脳、白銀こよりだよ！
And next! The brain of Hololive 6th gen Secret Society holoX, Hakui Koyori here!
ということで第2回もこうして皆さんに来ていただいたことで開催できてとても嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
I'm so happy that thanks to everyone coming today, we're able to hold the second edition of this! Please enjoy!
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
そして！今日ピアノは、えー、前回に引き続きウイングさんに弾いていただきますよ！
And today, playing the piano just like last time, we have Wing-san!
おー！
Woah!
一緒にみんなで礼するやつじゃない？
Isn't that the signal for us to all bow together?
じゃん！じゃん！じゃん！
Ta-da! Ta-da! Ta-da!
なにこれ？
What is this?
あ、これ日本の学校の…
Ah, this is like a Japanese school...
遅いですか？
Was it too late?
そうなんです！あ、じゃあもう一回！
That's right! Ah, let's try it one more time!
ピッ！ピッ！はい！はい！
Beep! Beep! Yes! Yes!
はい！ありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you so much!
ここも体験できた！学校が始まった！
We got to experience this too! School has started!
さあ始まりました！そして、えー、今回もですね、こちら完全生3Dライブ！
It has begun! And this time as well, this is a 100% fully live 3D performance!
最初から最後まで生で全部お届けいたしますので、優しい目で見守ってください！
We'll be delivering everything live from start to finish, so please watch over us warmly!
はい！
Yes!
ハッシュタグはこちら #holoAcousticLive となっております！
The hashtag for today is #holoAcousticLive!
イエーイ！
Yay!
そして、えーっと、ここには書いてないんですけども #博衣こより超重大告知 というハッシュタグもありまして
And although it's not written here, we also have the hashtag #HakuiKoyoriSuperMajorAnnouncement...
本日は途中で告知もありますので、ぜひ皆さん最後まで見ていってください！よろしくお願いします！
We have an announcement during the show, so please make sure to watch until the end!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
では！ここからは、ちょっと2人ずつ順番に歌っていくしっとりコーナーに、行こうかと思います！
Now then! From here on, we're moving into the mellow section where we'll sing in pairs!
最初に一緒に歌ってくれるのは…
The first one who will be singing with me is...
誰だ？誰だ？
Who is it? Who is it?
ガチャ！
Gacha!
ガチャじゃなかった！
It wasn't gacha!
ガチャで当たったのは AZKiー！
The one pulled from gacha is... AZKi!
イエーイ！
Yay!
それでは、他の皆さんはちょっとゆっくりしていってください！
Alright then, everyone else can go take a rest!
はーい！ありがとう！
Okay! Thank you!
元々私達喋るためだけに出てきてました！すみません！
We originally just came out to talk! Sorry about that!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ということで今日は「In Autumn」ということで秋っぽい曲を…
So today, with the theme "In Autumn", we gathered songs that feel like autumn...
いいですね！集めましたよ！
Sounds great! We gathered them!
いや、これは一緒に歌いたかった！
I really wanted to sing this song together!
そう、AZKiちゃんが言ってくれて、歌えることになって超ハッピーです！
Yeah, AZKi-chan suggested it, and I'm super happy we get to sing it!
超ハッピーです！選曲させていただきました！
Super happy! We selected these songs!
歌わせてもらいます！では、タイトルコールお伺いしちゃいましょうかね！
We'll be singing it for you! Now then, shall we have you do the title call?
それでは聴いてください。「暁の車」
Please listen... "Akatsuki no Kuruma".
風さそう
The wind invites...
木陰に うつむいていた
Looking down in the shade of the trees,
誰の身も知らぬ わたしを
Knowing no one, I...
わたしが見ていた
...was looking at myself.
逝く人の調べを
Playing the melody of the departing,
奏でる ギターら
the guitars resonate.
来ぬ人の 嘆きに
At the grief of the one who will not come,
星は落ちて
the stars fall.
行かないで
"Don't go!"
どんなに叫んでも
No matter how loudly I cry out,
オレンジの花びら
the orange petals
静かに 揺れるだけ
are merely swaying quietly.
やわらかな手に
Left behind in these gentle hands,
残された
remains...
手のひらの 記憶を 遠く
the memories in my palm. Far away,
冷えたさよなら つまびく
I pluck a cold goodbye.
優しい手にすがる 子供の心を
A child's heart clinging to a gentle hand,
燃えさかる車は 振り払い進む
the burning wheels push onward, shaking it off.
逝く人の 嘆きを 奏でて
Playing the grief of the departing,
ギターら
guitars,
胸の灯 激しく かき鳴らして
strum fiercely the flame in my heart.
哀しみに 染まらない 白さで
With a whiteness untainted by sorrow,
オレンジの花びら 揺れていた 夏の影に
orange petals swayed in the summer shadows.
やわらかな 日々を なくしても
Even if we lose those tender days,
赤く染めた
hands dyed in crimson...
手は 遥か 超えてゆく さよなら
...reach far beyond to farewell.
追いつむ...
Chasing after...
思い出を 焼き尽くして
Burning away all the memories,
進む大地に 懐かしく 芽吹いてゆく ものがあるの
on the advancing earth, something nostalgic sprouts.
暁の 車を見送る
Seeing off the wheel of dawn,
オレンジの花びら 揺れている
orange petals are swaying,
今もどこか
somewhere even now.
いつか見た 安らかな 夜明けを
Until I hold that peaceful dawn once seen...
もう一度 手にするまでは
...in my hands once more,
消さないで 灯火
do not extinguish the light.
車は
The wheels...
回るよ
...keep turning.
I am GOD'S CHILD
この腐敗した世界に堕とされた
Dropped into this corrupt world
How do I live on such a field?
こんなもののために生まれたんじゃない
I wasn't born for something like this
突風に埋もれる足取り
Footsteps buried in a sudden gust of wind
倒れそうになるのを
Just as I'm about to collapse...
この鎖が 許さない
...these chains won't allow it
不快に冷たい壁とか
Unpleasantly cold walls, and the like...
次はどれに弱さを許す？
Which ones will I allow my weakness to show to next?
私はまだ上手に 片付けられずに
I still haven't been able to deal with it properly
I am GOD'S CHILD
この腐敗した世界に堕とされた
Dropped into this corrupt world
How do I live on such a field?
こんなもののために生まれたんじゃない
I wasn't born for something like this
理由はもっと喋り続けて
Keep talking about the reasons more
私が見つめるまで
Until I can fall asleep
聞かないクスリばかり 転がってるけど
There are only ineffective medicines rolling around
ここにこんなものもないのに 一体何を信じれば
When there isn't even anything like that here, what on earth should I believe in?
早く哀しみを 背中に詰めやった
Quickly stuffing sorrow onto my back
いい加減 こんな思いじゃ どこにも居場所なんてない
Seriously, with feelings like this, there's no place for me anywhere
不快に冷たい壁とか
Unpleasantly cold walls, and the like...
次はどれに弱さを許す？
Which ones will I allow my weakness to show to next?
最後になど 手を伸ばさないで
Don't reach out your hand at the very end
貴方なら救い出して
If it's you, rescue me
私を 静寂から
From the silence...
I am GOD'S CHILD
この腐敗した世界に堕とされた
Dropped into this corrupt world
How do I live on such a field?
こんなもののために生まれたんじゃない
I wasn't born for something like this
I am GOD'S CHILD
哀しい音は 背中に爪痕をつけて
The sad sounds leave claw marks on my back
I can't hang on this world
こんな思いじゃ どこにも居場所なんてない
With feelings like this, there's no place for me anywhere
How do I live on such a field?
夕月夜 顔だす
An evening moon shows its face,
消えてく子供の声
as the voices of children fade away.
遠く遠くこの空のどこかに
Far, far away, somewhere in this sky,
君はいるんだろう
you must be out there.
夏の終わり 2人で抜け出した
At the end of summer, the two of us snuck away
この公園で見つけた
and found in this park
あの星座 なんだか覚えてる?
that constellation—do you somehow remember it?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace back my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
wanting to see the same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がパッと開く
Along with that fragrance, the fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are,
今すぐ駆けだしていきたいよ
I want to run to you right now.
真っ暗で何も見えない
It's pitch black and I can't see a thing;
怖くても大丈夫
even if I'm scared, I'll be okay.
数えきれない星空が
The countless stars in the night sky
今もずっとここにあるんだよ
are still right here, even now.
泣かないよ
I won't cry,
昔君と見た きれいな空だったから
because that sky I saw with you back then was so beautiful.
あの道まで響く 靴の音が耳に残る
The sound of footsteps resounding down that path lingers in my ears;
大きな自分の影を見つめて 想うのでしょう
staring at my own long shadow, I reflect on it all.
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに
Even though nothing should have changed at all,
切ない気持ちふくらんでく
this painful heartache keeps swelling inside me.
どんなに想ったって
No matter how much I long for you,
君はもういない
you're no longer here.
行きたいよ 君のそばに
I want to go to your side,
小さくても小さくても
even if I'm small, even if I'm tiny.
一番に君が好きだよ
You are the one I love most of all,
強く居られる
so I can stay strong.
願いを流れ星に
I quietly made a wish upon a shooting star,
そっと唱えてみたけれど
though I recited it softly...
泣かないよ
I won't cry,
届くだろう きれいな空に
hoping it will reach into that beautiful sky.
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I trace back my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
wanting to see the same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がパッと開く
Along with that fragrance, the fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are,
小さな手を握りしめて
clasping your small hand tightly.
泣きたいよ
I want to cry,
それは それは きれいな空だった
because that sky was so very beautiful.
願いを流れ星に
I quietly made a wish upon a shooting star,
そっと唱えてみたけれど
though I recited it softly...
泣きたいよ
I want to cry,
届かない想いを この空に...
sending my unreachable feelings into this sky...
ずっと一緒にいた
We were always together
二人で歩いた一本道
Walking along a single path together
二つに分かれて
Splitting into two
別々の方歩いてく
We each go our separate ways
寂しさで溢れたこの胸かかえて
Holding onto this heart filled with loneliness
今にも泣き出しそうな空見上げて
Looking up at the sky that seems about to cry
あなたを想った...
I thought of you...
君がいない夜だって そう no more cry もう泣かないよ
Even on nights without you, that's right, no more cry, I won't cry anymore
がんばっているからねって 強くなるからねって
Because I'm doing my best, because I'm growing stronger
君も見ているだろう この消えそうな三日月
You must be looking at it too, this crescent moon about to vanish
つながっているからねって 愛してるからねって
Because we're connected, because I love you
冷えきった手を
My freezing hands
一人であたためる日々
Days spent warming them all alone
君のぬくもり
Longing for your warmth
恋しくて 恋しくて
So dearly, so dearly
どれだけ電話で「好き」と言われたって
No matter how many times you say "I love you" over the phone
君に寄りかかる事はできない
I can't lean on you
涙をぬぐった...
I wiped away my tears...
君がいない夜だって そう no more cry もう泣かないよ
Even on nights without you, that's right, no more cry, I won't cry anymore
がんばっているからねって 強くなるからねって
Because I'm doing my best, because I'm growing stronger
今度いつ会えるんだろう
When will we be able to meet next?
それまでの電池は
My battery until then will be
抱きしめながら言った
Your words "I love you"
あなたの「愛してる」の一言
That you said while holding me tight
君がいない夜だって そう no more cry もう泣かないよ
Even on nights without you, that's right, no more cry, I won't cry anymore
がんばっているからねって
Because I'm doing my best
強くなるからねって
Because I'm growing stronger
君も見ているだろう この消えそうな三日月
You must be looking at it too, this crescent moon about to vanish
つながっているからねって 愛してるからねって
Because we're connected, because I love you
三日月 手をのばした
I reached my hand out to the crescent moon
君に届け この想い
Reach you, these feelings of mine
はい、ということで4曲続けて2人ずつお届けさせていただきました！
All right, with that, we've performed four songs back-to-back in pairs!
皆さん～！あ、集まれ～！集まれ～！
Everyone~! Ah, gather round! Gather round!
めっちゃいいじゃないですか～！
Wasn't that super awesome?!
最高じゃないですか～！すごい！
Isn't it just the best?! Amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
では、ちょっと2曲目から振り返ってみよう...
Now then, let's look back starting from the second song...
かと思いますけれども
I think so, but...
まずは AZKiと『赤い車』！
First, AZKi and "Akai Kuruma"!
いや、素晴らしかったですね！
Man, that was wonderful!
楽しい！この曲！
This song is so fun!
こよちゃんと歌えたのめっちゃ嬉しいです
I'm so happy I got to sing it with Koyo-chan!
こよも！嬉しい！
Koyo too! I'm so happy!
でもなんか秋にも捧げられるとは...
But to think it could also be dedicated to autumn...
あいだに挟まれて...
Getting caught in the middle...
横取りされちゃった
It got snatched away!
すみません、すみません
Sorry, sorry!
はい、やー、ちょくちょくピアノも素敵で
Yeah, the piano was wonderful throughout too.
いや本当にね、この曲フィーチャーしましてね
Yeah really, featuring this song...
あの、ギターあらっていうから、本当ギターが
They say there's guitar, so the guitar really...
すごい鳴る曲なんですけど、ピアノオンリーになると
...resonates in this song, but with piano only...
こういう感じなんだなって
...it feels like this, huh?
いや、良かったです！
Yeah, it was great!
しっとりやらせていただきました！
We got to perform it nice and mellow!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
めっちゃ真ん中気まずい！
It's super awkward standing in the middle!
あ、違う違う！
Ah, wait wait!
めっちゃ真ん中気まずい！
Standing in the middle is super awkward!
と、トワさまどうぞ！
T-Towa-sama, please go ahead!
こよね、もうね
Koyo, you know...
トワさまの声で再生されてたもん！
It was already playing back in Towa-sama's voice!
合いすぎ！
It fit so well!
え、歌えてたかな？
Eh, did I sing it well?
もう超良かった！
It was super good!
意外と緊張しちゃったんだけど...
I actually got surprisingly nervous...
え、めっちゃ良かった！
Eh, it was so good!
こよりがね、一生緊張してたんで...
Koyori was nervous the whole time, so...
すごいガチガチで...
...she was super stiff...
リハの方がゆっくりしてましたね！
I was more relaxed during rehearsal!
一応この歌詞見れるんですよ
You see, we can view the lyrics...
この歌いながら
...while singing.
で、なんかこよりのパートの
And for Koyori's parts...
歌詞が...
...the lyrics...
あ、バラされる！
Ah, you're gonna expose me!
とんでもないことになってて...
...were written in a crazy way...
な、なんて言えばいいの？あれ、なんて言語化すればいい？
How should I put it? How do I describe it?
伸ばしとか...
Like sustained notes...
「〜〜」って言うとか、おーを全部...
...or writing out "~~~" or "oh"s...
「おーおーおーおーおー」って...
...like "Oh-oh-oh-oh-oh"...
そうそう、全部書いてるの！
Right right, everything was written out!
全部文字に表すんですよ！
She literally spelled out every sound in characters!
で、なんか英語の部分とかも全部カタカナにして
And even the English parts were all in katakana,
ちょっとひどいなと思って消したんですけど
so I thought "this is terrible" and erased it...
あの、「アイ アン ガッ チャー アイ」って書いてあった...
But it was written like "I an gatcha ai"...
リハーサルの時は大爆笑したけど
We burst out laughing during rehearsal,
まあちゃんと歌えてよかったです
but I'm glad we were able to sing it properly!
本当すみませんでした！
I'm really sorry!
こよりのせいでね
Because of Koyori, right?
はい！そして...
Yes! And next...
こぼとね、『Planetarium』！
...with Kobo, "Planetarium"!
『Planetarium』, do you know?
"Planetarium", do you know?
あたらしい... いやいやいや、あたらしい！
New... No no no, it's new!
え、覚えたな！
Eh, you learned it!
え、初めて？ファーストタイム？
Eh, is it your first time?
そうそうそう！
Yeah yeah yeah!
すごーい！
Amazing!
素敵な曲だ！
It's a wonderful song!
もちろん！上手かった！
Of course! You were so good!
めっちゃ早く...
So quickly...
覚えた？
Did you learn it?
そうそう！めっちゃ早く覚えた！
Yeah yeah! I learned it super fast!
覚えた？すごい！
You did? Amazing!
素敵な音楽だ
It's lovely music.
こぼのボイスにピッタリ！
It suits Kobo's voice perfectly!
いやー、こよりんママ！
Yay, Koyorin Mama!
ラストのハーモニー頑張ってくれたんです、こぼが！
Kobo worked so hard on the harmony at the end!
本当に！素敵なハーモニーだった！
Really! It was such a beautiful harmony!
すごい！
Incredible!
ありがとう、テリマカシ！
Thank you, terima kasih!
ハモりグッド！
Harmony good!
本当？
Really?
うん、オーケー、グッド！
Yeah, okay, good!
それはめっちゃなんかインプロビゼーション...
That was very, like, improvisation...
あん？
Huh?
インプロビゼーション？
Improvisation?
インプロビゼーション？何？
Improvisation? What?
インプロビゼーション、良かったかな？
Was the improvisation good?
良かった！
It was good!
めっちゃバグス！
Very bagus!
イエーイ！めっちゃいい！
Yay! Super good!
めっちゃバグス！バグス？
Very bagus! Bagus?
そうそう、バグス！
Yeah yeah, bagus!
バグス！
Bagus!
イエス、バグス！
Yes, bagus!
かわいい！後で教えてもらおう！
So cute! Teach me later!
そして、にこたんとね
And then, with Niko-tan...
『三日月』を歌わせていただきました！めっちゃピッタリ！
...we got to sing "Mikazuki"! It fit so well!
いや、良かったです！
Yeah, it was wonderful!
にこたんもリハまで楽しんで歌ってるだけだったんですけど
Niko-tan was just casually enjoying singing up until rehearsal...
立った瞬間緊張しちゃって...
...but the moment I stood on stage, I got nervous!
皆さんもそうだと思うんですけど...
I think everyone felt that way too, though...
嘘つけー！
Lies!
嘘つけだな！
Total lie!
とんでもなく上手かったよ！
You were insanely good!
本当ですか？良かったです！
Really? I'm glad!
ここに立ち続けてるこよ先輩もなんかすごいなと思って
Seeing Koyo-senpai standing up here continuously was amazing.
顔あわせた瞬間ちょっと、泣き虫なんで...
The moment we made eye contact, since I'm a crybaby...
ええー！
Ehh!
ちょっとまたウルっときちゃって...
...I started getting teary-eyed again...
本当？本当？
Really? Really?
大変だった！
It was intense!
こよ勝手にこの曲にこたんのこと色々考えちゃって...
Koyo couldn't help thinking about all kinds of things about Niko-tan during this song...
なんかすごいね、思い浮かべながら...
...and while imagining all that...
マジですか！
Seriously?!
大事に歌わせていただきました！
...I sang it with so much care!
にこたんも実は結構思い入れが...色々思い出して考えました！
Actually, Niko-tan also had strong emotional attachment... I thought of many memories!
マジか！そういうこと？！
Seriously?! Is that so?!
エモいよ、先輩！
That's so emotional, Senpai!
色んな意味でもすごく合ってるし、声にも合ってるし
It fits so well in many ways, and it suits your voice too!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
最高でした！
It was the best!
みんなに届けられて良かったです！
I'm so glad we could deliver it to everyone!
お疲れ様！
Great job!
お疲れ様でした！
Thank you for your hard work!
Great job everyone!
全曲出てるのね！
You're in every song!
そうですね、今回は... いつもだったらね
That's right, this time... Usually, you know...
本当はもっとシャッフルしたかったんですけど
...I actually wanted to shuffle it more,
今日はちょっと重大告知もあるので！
but today we also have an important announcement!
頑張って歌おうかなってことで
So I thought I'd give it my all and sing,
全部お邪魔しました！
and joined in on all of them!
通ってると思うよ！
I think that came through!
すごい！
Amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
凄く楽しかったけど、緊張しちゃいました！
It was so fun, but I got nervous!
はい！
Yes!
それでは！
Well then!
この後はですね...
After this...
ちょっとみんなと...
...with everyone...
スペシャルなメドレーを！
...a special medley...
歌いたいと思います！
...we'd like to sing!
まだあるんですか？！
There's still more?!
まだまだありますよ！
There's still plenty more!
続いてはですね、やっぱりちょっとね
Next up, well...
こよりがずっと居るのもな、みたいな気持ちがあって
...I felt like, "maybe having Koyori around the whole time is a bit much,"
みんなのシャッフルを聞きたかったので！
and I wanted to hear everyone else's shuffle!
お！
Oh!
オリジナル曲を！
Original songs!
スペシャルシャッフルメドレーさせていただきます！
We'll be doing a Special Shuffle Medley!
イエーイ！
Yay!
それでは！
So then!
最初に歌っていただく...
Singing first...
AZKiと...
...AZKi and...
にこたんを残して...
...leaving Niko-tan on stage...
後の3人はお暇しましょうかね
...the remaining three of us shall take our leave!
はじまります！
It's starting!
ねこぽんた... 他力になっちゃいましたね。
Nekoponta... we ended up relying on others, didn't we?
き、来ましたね！
I-It's here!
ござるちゃんの枠でね
On Gozaru-chan's stream, right?
ちょっとドキドキの2人のデュエットをさせていただこうかなと
We thought we'd perform a slightly nervous duet together...
思います！
...I hope you enjoy it!
ぜひお願いします！
Please, go ahead!
では、準備はよろしいですか？
Now then, are you ready?
はい！
Yes!
それではお聞きください。せーの！
Then please take a listen. Ready, set...
スペシャルメドレー！
Special Medley!
息をしている
I am breathing,
だから生きている
which is why I am alive.
何度もずっと
Again and again, forever,
言葉を尽くしてきたんだ
I've poured my heart into these words.
息をしている
I am breathing,
夜に見えている
visible in the night.
青が染み出す 私にとっての何か
The blue seeps through, something meaningful to me.
鼓動が孤独している
My heartbeat beats in solitude.
ここはいつも変わらずに
This place remains unchanged, as always.
急かし続ける
Constantly rushing forward,
ボタンひとつのいのち
a life controlled by a single button.
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの？
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよ ねぇ
I feel like I'm going to fade away—understand me, please understand, hey.
本当のところどうなの いずれは卒業するんでしょう
What's the truth really? We'll graduate eventually, right?
日常に戻ったら 私は居なくなるの
Once we return to ordinary life, will I disappear?
いのちのような
Like a life,
夢を見ているよ
I'm dreaming a dream.
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye.
自信なんて無かった 1人だって良かった
I had no confidence, I was fine being alone.
プライドに隠れて
Hiding behind my pride,
誰かの視線気になってばかりで 閉じこもっていた
always worrying about others' gazes, I shut myself away.
綺麗だなんて思えなくて 笑えなかったんだ
I couldn't think of myself as beautiful, I couldn't even smile.
涙で滲んだ画面の向こう ふいに溶けた心
Beyond the screen blurred with tears, my heart suddenly thawed.
触れてくれた声
The voice that reached out to touch me—
君のおかげで笑えたよ
thanks to you, I was able to smile.
その言葉がずっと この胸を灯す
Those words light up my chest forever,
ただ一つの光
as a single guiding light.
Fly high, take me higher 消えそうな声を歌に変えて
Fly high, take me higher, turning my fading voice into song.
弱さ抱きしめながら 届けと叫ぶように燃やす炎
Embracing my weakness, I burn like a flame, shouting to reach you.
Fly high, take me higher 君の明日を照らしたい
Fly high, take me higher, I want to illuminate your tomorrow.
黙ってうつむいて 空の色さえ
Slumped in silence, not even knowing the color of the sky,
知らない私の
my former self—
声で君が笑った
you smiled at my voice.
あの日から世界は眩しくて
Ever since that day, the world has been so bright,
私は私を好きになって
I've come to like who I am,
なくさないように息をする
and I breathe so I won't lose it.
暗闇のような
Like darkness...
真ん中で今も
Even now in the middle of it,
泣いているのは
the one who is crying...
君が映る世界が
As the world reflecting you
悲しくなるほど優しくから
grows so gentle it turns sad,
苦しくなるほど遠いから
so distant it becomes painful...
じくじくとうずく甘い熱は
The sweet heat aching throbbingly,
閉じ込めていたのに
though I had locked it away,
痛くてこぼれた
spilled out from the pain.
君と私の体と
Between your body and mine,
体の間にある
in the space between us,
ひどく薄い皮膚さえも邪魔になるくらい
even the thinnest skin feels like an obstacle.
その鼓膜 その心臓を
Your eardrums, your heart...
ずっと奥に触れられたら
If I could touch deep inside,
君はまた笑うのかな
would you smile once again?
どうか君まで届け
Please, let it reach you.
I don't recognize the face staring back at me today
I guess it's time to change, la-la-la-la
When I don't feel like myself, I don't need someone else
Can't stand just one phase and now I'm zero to 100
You can't cage me up, I'm the key
A chameleon in high heels
They can slick-a, slick-a slide, slick-a, slick-a slide like me
Every night, I'm just moving to the rhythm of a different light
Say goodbye, 'cause tomorrow I'm the girl you met tonight
Switch it up, ooh-ooh-ooh! Switch it up, ooh-ooh-ooh!
I just wanna feel my heart, just feel my heart go boom-boom-boom!
Every time I've had enough of who I was, I switch it up again
いいね いいね このまま 溢れ出しちゃうくらいに
Nice, nice, just like this, to the point of overflowing!
あっと チョイっと そのまま これを 3滴か 4滴か
Just a tiny drop, just like that! Should I add 3 drops or 4 drops?
チョチョチョ チョイっと チョイっと 私でなきゃないって 言われて よかった
Just a bit, just a bit! I'm so glad they said it had to be me!
サンシャイン 初々しいな 君も言っちゃって 言っちゃって
Sunshine, so innocent! You say it too, say it too!
ピンクになっちゃえ 全人類 両手にピースで ハイハッピー
Turn pink, all of humanity! Peace signs in both hands, super happy!
飛んでけ 羞恥心 持ってけ 白衣
Fly away, embarrassment! Take my lab coat!
ピンクになっちゃえよ 全人類 誰も彼も 全部
Turn pink, all of humanity! Every single one of you!
いいでしょ？ いいよね？ 絶対 楽しいよ
It's fine, right? Isn't it? It's definitely gonna be fun!
ピンクになっちゃえよ 全人類
Turn pink, all of humanity!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
High! High! High! High!
ピンクになっちゃえよ 全人類
Turn pink, all of humanity!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
High! High! High! High!
ピンク色のあとも 世界を救う！
Even after turning pink, we will save the world!
オリジナル曲スペシャルメドレーでした！
And that was our original song special medley!
今歌った最後の曲はですね、本日リリースしたJunkyさんによる「ピンクになっちゃえ」という曲なんですけれども、
The last song we just sang was "Pink ni Naccha e" by Junky-san, which was released today!
このステージ、そしてみんなの手元もちょっとピンクに染め上げさせていただいたところで...
And now that this stage, as well as everyone's penlights, have been dyed pink...
ピンクになっちゃった！なっちゃった！みんなちょっとピンク！イェーイ！
It turned pink! It turned pink! Everyone's a bit pink! Yay!
はい！ということで、ここでこよからの超超超重大なお知らせをさせていただこうと思います！
Alright! So, now I'd like to make a super, super, super important announcement from Koyori!
ですがね、告知後に全員でもう1曲歌いますので...
However, after the announcement, all five of us will sing one more song...
え、そうだったの？
Wait, really?
私知らない...
I didn't know that...
全然何も知らないやん！何も知らないトワ様！
You didn't know anything at all! Towa-sama didn't know a thing!
ということで皆さん、最後までチャンネルはそのままで見ていってくださいねー！
So everyone, please keep watching on this channel until the very end!
どうぞご覧ください！
Please take a look!
特報
[Special Announcement]
まずオリジナル曲を作りたい！
First, I want to make an original song!
なんと博衣こより、初めての...
Surprisingly, Hakui Koyori's very first...
FIRST STEPのその先へ
[Beyond the FIRST STEP]
初の全国流通！ 2ndアルバムリリース！
[First Nationwide Distribution! 2nd Album Release!]
12/2 RELEASE!!
AKIHABARAゲーマーズでリリースイベント開催決定！
[Release Event Confirmed at AKIHABARA GAMERS!]
こよりにはいっぱいいっぱい、夢がある
Koyori has so, so many dreams,
全ての夢を叶えるのが夢
so my dream is to fulfill all my dreams,
叶えていけるように
so that I can keep making them come true.
夢のソロライブに みんなを連れて行きたい
I want to bring everyone along to my dream solo live.
博衣こより 1st Live 開催決定
[Hakui Koyori 1st Live Confirmed]
2026.12.22
TOKYO GARDEN THEATER
Hakui Koyori 1st Live Dream Spark
#夢煌めくこより
[#DreamSparklingKoyori]
はい！ということで！
Alright! So!
2026年12月22日 東京ガーデンシアターにて
On December 22, 2026, at Tokyo Garden Theater,
博衣こより 1st Live Dream Sparkの開催が決定いたしました！
Hakui Koyori 1st Live "Dream Spark" has been confirmed!
イエーイ！おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
はい！ついに夢のひとつであるソロライブが決まりました！ありがとうございます！
Yes! One of my dreams, a solo live, has finally been decided! Thank you so much!
はい、今年できるとは思っていなかったので
Yes, I didn't think I'd be able to do it this year,
みんなもちょっと早くてびっくりしてると思うんですけれども
so I think everyone is a bit surprised that it's so soon,
精一杯頑張っていくので応援よろしくお願いします！
but I'll do my best, so please support me!
え、そして今回のライブのハッシュタグは『#夢煌めくこより』となっております！
And the hashtag for this live concert is "#夢煌めくこより"!
ぜひこちらで呟いてください！
Please tweet using this hashtag!
ちなみに、セカンドアルバムのハッシュタグも同じ『夢煌めくこより』でやっていくので
By the way, the hashtag for the 2nd album will also be "#夢煌めくこより",
どんどんポストしていただけると嬉しいです！
so I'd be very happy if you keep posting with it!
ライブの詳しい情報については、後日発表予定となります。
Detailed information about the live concert will be announced at a later date.
皆さんまずは、12月22日、にゃんにゃんの日、ぜひ予定をあけて待っててくださーい！
Everyone, first of all, please keep December 22nd open and look forward to it!
そして、さらに！こよりのセカンドアルバム『Chemical Spark』が12月2日に発売決定となりました！
And what's more, Koyori's 2nd album "Chemical Spark" will be released on December 2nd!
はい！今回はホロライブオフィシャルショップ限定販売の完全生産限定盤と
Yes! This time there's a Complete Production Limited Edition sold exclusively at the Hololive Official Shop,
こより初の全国流通での販売もある通常盤の2種類となります！
and a Standard Edition, which is Koyori's first nationwide distributed release!
アルバムには書き下ろしの新曲のほか
In addition to brand-new original songs,
CD限定の曲などもありますので、ぜひともお聞きください！
there are CD-exclusive tracks as well, so please listen to it!
まずは完全生産限定盤の同梱物についてご紹介します！こちらです！
First, let me introduce the contents of the Complete Production Limited Edition! Here they are!
はい！アルバムのイラストを使ったアクスタやホロカのほか
Yes! Along with an acrylic stand and Holoca card featuring the album illustration,
こよりからの思いを込めたお手紙
a letter filled with Koyori's feelings,
そして直筆で皆さんにサインを書いたアナザージャケットがついてきます！
and an alternative jacket hand-signed for everyone are included!
買ってくれた助手くんみんなのために頑張るので、ぜひお手に入れてください！
I'll do my best for all the Assistants who buy it, so please get your hands on it!
とっても豪華な六角形、このね、こよりの頭についているベンゼン環と
It comes in a very luxurious hexagonal box, in the same shape as the benzene ring on Koyori's head,
同じ形のスペシャルBOXパッケージとなっております！お楽しみに！
making it a Special Box Package! Look forward to it!
さらに！なんと完全生産限定盤の予約特典として
Furthermore! As a pre-order bonus for the Complete Production Limited Edition,
先ほど発表したソロライブの先行抽選シリアルコードがついてまいります！
a serial code for the early ticket lottery of the solo live announced earlier will be included!
シリアルコードが付属するのは完全生産限定盤のみ！
The serial code is only included with the Complete Production Limited Edition!
そして、期間もあるのでお気をつけください！
Also, please note that there is a limited period!
シリアルコードはご文1件に1つ付きますが
One serial code is provided per order,
複数購入しても応募で使えるコードは1つだけなのでご注意ください。
but please note that even if you purchase multiple copies, only one code can be used for application.
そしてシリアルコードはですね、ライブチケット抽選への応募券となりまして
And the serial code serves as an application ticket for the live ticket lottery,
当選を保証するものではないこと
and does not guarantee winning.
そして当選時にチケット購入の代金も追加で必要になりますので、そちらはご了承ください。
Also, if you win, an additional ticket purchase fee will be required, so please keep that in mind.
そのほか詳しくはホロライブオフィシャルショップの販売ページを必ずチェックしてくださいね！
For all other details, please be sure to check the Hololive Official Shop sales page!
はい、そしてこちらが通常盤の同梱物です！
Yes, and here are the included items for the Standard Edition!
初回プレス限定で、全5種類のランダムアナザージャケットが1枚入っています！
Exclusive to the initial press, it contains one random alternative jacket out of 5 types!
これはファーストアルバムと同じ形にさせていただきました！
We kept the same format as the 1st album!
それぞれ違ったイラストレーターさんにイラストを描き下ろしていただいておりますよ！
Each artwork was newly drawn by a different illustrator!
ちょっと動物園になってますけれども（笑）、はい。
It's a bit like a zoo (laughs), but yes.
さらにですね、そこに数量限定ランダムで...
Furthermore, in a limited quantity, randomly included...
こよりの直筆サインが入っているかもしれません！
Koyori's handwritten signature might be included!
当たったらラッキーということで、おみくじ感覚でご購入ください。
If you get one, you're lucky! Think of it like drawing a fortune when you buy.
そして、店舗さんでの特典アイテムはこのようになっております。
And here are the bonus items available at different stores!
ドン！
Ta-da!
はい、それぞれ素敵なアイテムをご用意させていただきました！
Yes, we've prepared wonderful items for each store!
そしてなんとですね、秋葉原ゲーマーズ本店さんでリリースイベントを2024年1月8日に開催いたします！
And what's more, a release event will be held at Gamers Main Store in Akihabara on January 8, 2024!
ゲーマーズさんでCDを予約・購入すると抽選に応募できますので、詳細はゲーマーズさんのウェブサイトをチェックしてみてください！
If you pre-order or buy the CD at Gamers, you can enter the raffle, so check Gamers' website for details!
ちなみに、先ほど披露したアルバムにも収録される、JON-YAKITORYさん作詞のえー新曲「ピンクになっちゃえ」のMVを、このライブ終了後にプレミア公開させていただきますので、ぜひ見ていってください！
By the way, the MV for the new song "Pink ni Natchae" written by JON-YAKITORY, which is included in the album we just showed, will premiere after this live stream, so please watch it!
JON-YAKITORYさんといつも一緒にやってる103さんに、103さん節のMV作っていただいてますので見てください！
103, who always works with JON-YAKITORY, created an MV full of 103's signature style, so please check it out!
以上、アルバムはこの後21時より予約開始です！ご注目ください！
That's all for the album, pre-orders start tonight at 21:00! Please look forward to it!
さらに、実はもう一つ重大告知がありまして…
Furthermore, I actually have one more major announcement...
ドドン！
Ta-da!
はい！TOKYO FMさんにて、10月に1ヶ月限定の特別番組放送が決定いたしましたー！イエーイ！
Yes! A 1-month special radio program on TOKYO FM has been confirmed for October! Yay!
大好きなラジオ、そして冠番組が、よく聴いていたTOKYO FMさんでできるのがすごく嬉しいです！ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy to host a solo show for my beloved radio medium on TOKYO FM, which I've listened to so often! Thank you so much!
オンエア日時などは後日発表させていただきますので、お楽しみに！
The broadcast schedule and details will be announced later, so stay tuned!
告知は以上となります！皆さん、大変お待たせいたしました！
That's all for the announcements! Everyone, thank you so much for waiting!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
お待たせいたしました！遅くなって申し訳ございません。
Thanks for waiting! Sorry to keep you all waiting.
ありがとうございます！じゃあちょっと元いた位置にね、戻り…
Thank you! Alright, let's head back to our original positions...
はい！ということで、お届けいたしました「holoAcousticLive」第2回だったんですけれども…
Yes! So that was the second edition of "holoAcousticLive"...
この後ね、もう1曲歌うので、皆さんちょっと待っててくだいね！みんなで歌いますからね！
We have one more song after this, so please wait a bit! We'll all sing together!
まずはちょっと皆さんに、1人ずつ感想とか、告知とかあったらしていってください！ではニコたん！
First, let's have everyone share their thoughts or announcements one by one! Niko-tan, go ahead!
いや、あのー、本当に一番の後輩が言わせてもらうのもアレなんですけど…
Well, it feels a bit weird for the newest junior like me to say this, but...
こよ先輩の本当に頑張り屋さんなところがいろんところから感じられて…
I could feel how hard Koyori-senpai works in every single aspect...
最初さ、トワ様がさ、歌詞のこと言ってたやん？「笑っちゃうわ」とか思ってたら、なんかそこにも感動してきちゃって…
At first, when Towa-sama mentioned the lyrics, I thought "That's so funny," but then I ended up feeling deeply moved by it...
一生懸命やってね、愛あんガチャ愛ある…
Watching her work so hard with so much love...
愛あんガチャーは本当ごめんだけど笑う…
Sorry, but "Aian Gacha" was really funny...
本当にこんな素敵なライブに参加させてもらえたこと、そして重大発表も本当におめでとうございます！
Thank you so much for letting me participate in such a wonderful live stream, and congratulations on all the big announcements!
またぜひ参加させてください！
Please let me participate again sometime!
こぼちゃん！ / まずは、セカンドアルバムおめでとう！
Kobo-chan! / First, congratulations on your second album!
サンキュー！テリマカシ！ / ファーストソロライブおめでとう！
Thank you! Terima kasih! / Congratulations on your first solo live!
サンキュー！テリマカシ！ / 私は歌うのが好き。だからここは嬉しい！
Thank you! Terima kasih! / I love singing! So I'm really happy to be here!
ゲストに呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me as a guest!
来てくれてありがとう！ / こぼ上手！
Thank you for coming! / Kobo, you're so good!
欲しいもの何でも言うのよ！プレゼントあげる！ / 高いもの！高いものでもいいのよ！
Tell me whatever you want! I'll give you a gift! / Something expensive! Even expensive stuff is fine!
マンション！ / マンション？！マンションは無理！
A condo! / A condo?! A condo is impossible!
後でね！後で何でもいいのよ！ / ありがとうね、本当に！
Later, okay? Anything later is fine! / Thank you so much, really!
また歌おう！ / はい！いつでも！
Let's sing again! / Yes! Anytime!
本当？呼んじゃうよ！ / Yes!
Really? I'll invite you again! / Yes!
とても可愛い！ありがとー！
So cute! Thank you!
そしてトワ様！
And Towa-sama!
はい！みんなと歌えたのがすごい嬉しかったです、まずは。
Yes! First of all, I was so happy to sing with everyone.
あとね、やっぱりニコも言ってたけど、こよりがね、色んな企画とかで絡むというか、一緒になることがあるんですけども…
And as Niko said, I often get to interact or collaborate with Koyori on various projects...
1つ1つのことに全力投球というか、一生懸命頑張ってるのを裏でも見てきたんで、ソロライブできて本当におめでとうという気持ちです。
I've seen behind the scenes how she gives 100% to every single thing, so I'm truly happy for her solo live and want to say congratulations.
ありがとうございます！頑張ります！ / 今日も頑張ってました、皆さん！褒めてあげてください、こよりちゃんのことを！
Thank you so much! I'll do my best! / She worked super hard today too, everyone! Please shower Koyori-chan with praise!
もっと頑張ります！緊張しました… / ソロライブまで大変かもしれないけど、全力で頑張ってくださいね！
I'll work even harder! I was so nervous... / It might be tough until the solo live, but give it your all!
ありがとうございます、先輩！ / はい！先輩です！
Thank you, senpai! / Yes, I'm your senpai!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
はい！まずはソロライブ開催とアルバム発売、おめでとうございます！
Yes! First, congratulations on holding your solo live and releasing your album!
本当にこよちゃんは何倍頑張ってるんだっていうぐらい…
Honestly, Koyori works so many times harder than anyone else...
たくさん努力を多分いっぱいしてきて
Having put in so much effort...
今日があって
...leading up to today...
なんかあのもうティザーで泣きそうになりましたよ
...seeing the teaser almost brought me to tears!
本当だね！ / 分かる分かる！
That's so true! / I know, right!
泣きそうになっちゃった。これが全部今に繋がって...
It almost made me cry. All of that led to this moment...
今日があるし、これからまた忙しくなると思いますけど
We have today, and I'm sure things will get busy again...
みんなにいっぱい夢を与えてくださいね！
...so please keep giving everyone lots of dreams!
頑張ります！ / 決まった！
We will! / Awesome!
今日はありがとうございました！ / こちらこそ！
Thank you so much for today! / Thank you as well!
またぜひ第3回も...
We hope you'll host a 3rd stream...
高緊張...
I was so nervous...
さすがにちょっとおこがましいかなと思いながら...
I felt a bit presumptuous even asking...
一緒にやってるような気持ちになって、勝手に...
...but I felt like we were doing this together...
ありがとうございます！いつもお世話になってます！
Thank you so much! Thank you for everything as always!
はい、ということでね、今日はちょっと...
Yes! So today, I was...
緊張しすぎたし、ハッチャケすぎて息切れましたし...
...a bit too nervous, and ran out of breath from going wild...
ちょっと恥ずかしい感じなんですけど、トータル自分は...
...it's a little embarrassing, but overall...
みんなと一緒に歌えたこの場がとっても楽しくて幸せでございました！本当にありがとうございます！
...singing here together with everyone was so fun and happy! Thank you so much!
こちらこそです！ / この後も精進いたしますので...
Likewise! / I'll keep working hard from now on...
ぜひお見守りください。よろしくお願いします！
...so please keep watching over me. Thank you!
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
それでは... お知ら... お買い物とか大丈夫ですか？
Now then... wait, are there any announcements or anything?
いいでしょ！大丈夫ですよ！あなたが主役なんですから！
It's fine! You're the star of the show!
ねねのチャンネル登録をしてください！よろしくお願いします！
Please subscribe to Nene's channel! Thank you!
概要欄にありますので！よろしくお願いします！
Links are in the description box below! Thank you!
それじゃあ、最後にちょっと一緒に歌わせていただきます！
Well then, lastly, let me sing a little together with you!
はい！では最後に... お聞きください！
Yes! Then lastly... please listen!
Our Bright Parade!
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining bright!
呼び合う声を合図に
With our calling voices as the signal
パレード パレード パレード 探しに行く
Parade, parade, parade, going out to search
スターターはどこだって
Wherever the starter may be
イェーイ！ hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade 開催決定おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations on hololive 4th fes. Our Bright Parade!
おめでとう！みんな本当にありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you so much, everyone!
ただ 独り言 呟いた
I just whispered a monologue to myself
ただ 始まりたくて 走った
Just wanting to begin, I ran forward
遠く 暗がりに 灯った
Far off, a light shone in the dark
それは 眩し過ぎたの名前
That was the name of something far too dazzling
それは 優し過ぎる思い出
That was a memory that was far too gentle
もっと 近付けと 手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer
思いがけず 結び合った ほら 今
Unexpectedly, we joined together, look, right now
迷子は 僕らになった
The lost ones became us
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, shining bright!
悔しさも 愛おしさも 連れて おいで
Bringing both regret and preciousness along, come on
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings—we can take flight!
ささやかな 祈りは 光
A modest prayer is light
終わり無き 兆し
An endless sign
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
Finding you is something I can be proud of
ここから これから Our Bright Parade
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade
まだ 頼りない 予感を
Still an unreliable premonition
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing it, it's nothing to be ashamed of
誰も 解けない おまじない
An incantation no one can break
いつか また会える おまじない
An incantation to meet again someday
あの日 ゼロから 始まった ストーリー
A story that started from zero that day
数え切れない言葉 奇跡のような想い出さ
Countless words, memories like miracles
ほら 今 僕らを 一つと呼ぼう
Look, right now, let me call us one
パレード パレード パレード 美しいんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, it's beautiful!
許し合える 切ない 夜は 煌めく
Even painful nights where we forgive each other sparkle
雨 晴れ 鐘 また隣 空
Rain, clear skies, bells, again by our side, the sky
ふさわしい 旅路と
A fitting journey
今日は 君と 歩くことさ
Today, it's about walking with you.
君と 歩くことなんだ
It's all about walking together with you.
「ただいま」を聞けば
When I hear "I'm home,"
「おかえり」て叫ぶよ
I shout back "Welcome home!"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't that so natural?
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! We're shining bright!
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
What fills up the darkness is you and me!
パレード パレード パレード 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade! We're shining bright!
悔しさも 愛おしさも 募らせて
Gathering up all our regrets and affection...
おいで 風 夢 羽 飛び立ってるさ
Come on! Wind, dreams, wings—we're taking flight!
ささやかな祈りは
A modest prayer...
光 終わりなき兆し
...is light, a sign of something endless.
君と 飛び込んでいく 素敵なスタートさ
Diving in with you, what a wonderful start!
ここから これから Our Bright Parade Parade
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade, Parade!
Our Bright Parade Parade
ありがとう！
Thank you!
超超超! 重大告知アリ!
[Super Super Super Big Announcement!]